Vikram Solanki

North York, Ontario, Canada, M2J 1L6 (437) 755-1956 | vikramsolanki25@gmail.com

behance.net/vikramsolanki25

in linkedin.com/in/vikram-solanki

Sr. Product Designer crafting products that enhance lives and inspire positive change in organizations. With 10+ years of experience in designing and advocating for users, and a strong background in technology, I integrate empathy, creativity, and culture to create memorable experiences that drive customer engagement.



Experience

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

Sr. UX Designer / Moody's Analytics - Toronto, Canada (Contract)

- Currently working on Moody's top-selling SaaS application, CreditLens, the largest in its category. This solution aids financial institutions in making informed commercial lending decisions and offers enhanced risk assessment capabilities.
- Established a direct feedback channel for users and implemented high-demand features, including custom email notifications and GenAl capabilities, resulting in a 15% increase in CSAT scores.
- Collaborate with product, business, and user research teams to gather comprehensive insights and requirements, as well as to understand and document user behaviors and needs.
- Lead design workshops with product teams to refine and polish ideas, ensuring effective collaboration with product, business and engineering teams.
- Transform user needs and insights into functional prototypes that align design strategies with company goals.
- Ensure the user experience is prioritized in all design decisions, leading to products that are intuitive, and effective and that set industry benchmarks.
- Monitor user behavior and engagement, and identify opportunities to enhance the overall user experience across all
 channels while ensuring seamless experiences across different product areas.
- Foster an efficient, motivated, and creative team environment that encourages continuous learning.
- Co-create and manage a robust design system, ensuring consistency across all Moody's banking applications and evolving
 with industry trends and accessibility guidelines.

APR 2020 - MAR 2023 (3 yrs)

Sr. Product Designer / Kotak Mahindra Bank - Mumbai, India

- Handled multiple digital projects, including investment platform Kotak Cherry, banking platform Kotak Bank app, and e-commerce platform KayMall and ONDC.
- Established, mentored, and led a design team of six multidisciplinary designers. Led design reviews, facilitated team grooming sessions, and mentored junior designers to ensure high-quality user experiences, improve team collaboration, and feedback culture, and promote individual growth.
- Revamped Kotak Cherry App and customer journeys with design thinking methodology, resulting in a 108% increase in customer conversion and a 135% increase in user engagement within its first quarter.
- Developed design strategies, information architecture, user-centric journeys, wireframes, and prototypes while driving innovation through proof-of-concepts (POCs).

- Managed project timelines and estimations for upcoming sprints and collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver
 on time, monitoring progress and mitigating risks to achieve project goals with Agile design methodology.
- Conducted qualitative and quantitative user research to identify user needs, pain points, and behaviors, translating data into actionable design decisions and identifying gaps in usability.
- Co-created a platform-agnostic design system for Kotak Bank, ensuring consistency across all projects.
- Provided inspiring design vision and expertise to stakeholders and teams, and proactively conducted design workshops to improve the organization's UX maturity and educate teams and business partners.
- Collaborated and communicated complex and effective solutions to clients, stakeholders, and other teams.

JUL 2016 - MAR 2020 (3 yrs 9 mos)

UI/UX Designer / 5nance.com - Mumbai, India

- Led the redesign of the mobile app and established a new design system, overseeing projects through initial concept, execution, and evolution.
- Successfully led multiple projects, including the 5nance.com app, SaaS platform Surakshchakra for insurance agents driving a 63% month-over-month growth in the first quarter of launch, and B2B platform for investment advisors.
- Conducted user research and usability tests, analyzing and documenting findings to inform design decisions.
- Developed design strategies and user journeys for major projects, collaborating with cross-functional teams and stakeholders to deliver functional, user-friendly products that meet high quality and timeline.
- Established and implemented an Agile design process in the organization that streamlined workflows and ensured the timely delivery of projects, resulting in a high level of success.
- Executed visual design for digital products, including user interface design, iconography, and typography, that elevated the brand and resulted in a modern and cohesive user experience.
- Provided design support to the CEO in producing branded material for funding and oversaw the launch of all projects.

JAN 2015 - JUL 2016 (1 yr 6 mos)

Sr. Software Developer / 5nance.com - Mumbai, India

- Led a team of 4 front-end developers in spearheading the development of efficient and effective code using HTML/CSS, jQuery, and DevOps methodologies.
- Scheduled and conducted weekly meetings to ensure consistency in code and design components and oversaw code libraries to ensure the reuse of code in the development life cycle.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including product management and quality assurance, to ensure that the software development process met the organization's standards.
- Successfully managed agile software development projects, consistently delivering on time with high quality.
- Developed innovative and intuitive statistical graphics using data visualization techniques with D3.js, enhancing the user experience and delivering valuable insights.

SEP 2013 - DEC 2014 (1 yr 4 mos)

Software Developer / Technocrat Solutions - Mumbai, India

- Successfully handled a Windows desktop application built on the .NET framework for the Mumbai Police Recruitment division, generating \$20,000 in annual revenue, with a focus on delivering exceptional customer satisfaction.
- Designed and implemented robust Microsoft SQL databases for multiple applications, ensuring data integrity and security. Built reusable front-end HTML and CSS code and libraries to streamline development workflows.
- Developed efficient server-side code to maintain high-quality products, while consistently meeting architectural, design, and development task estimates.

Education

AUG 2009 - MAY 2013

B.E Information Technology / Atharva College of Engineering

Mumbai, India

AUG 2006 - MAY 2009

Diploma in Information Technology / Thakur Polytechnic

Mumbai, India

Certifications

FEB 2023

IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

Credentials 🗹

OCT 2018

HFI Certified Usability Analyst

Badge #: 2018-7183

Credentials 🗹

OCT 2016

ImaginXP - UX JumpStarter

Pune, India

Skills

| Design thinking | User research | Interaction design |
|-----------------|-------------------|----------------------|
| Mentoring | Wireframes | Micro-animations |
| Collaboration | Prototyping | Heuristic evaluation |
| Leadership | Visual design | Data visualization |
| User journeys | Usability testing | Agile Framework |
| Product Design | Design Systems | HTML5/CSS3 |